Preliminary Guide to the Howard W. Hallman papers, 1945-2003 MS2283
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Neighborhood Topics: Fairs and Festivals, Circa 1980 (Box 51, Folder 3)
- Neighborhood Topics: school decentralization, 1969-1970 (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Neighborhood Topics: schools reuse, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 5)
- Neighborhood Topics: traffic problems, 1979 August (Box 51, Folder 6)
- Neighborhood Topics: neighborhoods - misc., 1976-1983 (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Urban Policy: Notes, writings on urban policy, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 8)
- Urban Policy: Urban Policy Nat'l Conference of State Legislatures, 1977-1978 (Box 51, Folder 9)
- Urban Policy: National Urban Coalition -jobs and housing, 1978 May (Box 51, Folder 10)
- Urban Policy: CEO urban policy, 1977 December (Box 51, Folder 11)
- Urban Policy: Federal Reserve System and Reinvestment, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 12)
- Urban Policy: Illinois nieghborhood development corporation (South Side banks), 1983 (Box 51, Folder 13)
- Urban Policy: Wisconsin Housing and Neighborhood Conservation program, 1981 January (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Urban Policy: mortgage review boards, 1977 September (Box 52, Folder 2)
- Urban Policy: financial and real estate associations, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 3)
- Urban Policy: misc., 1980 December (Box 52, Folder 4)
- Partnerships: misc., 1984 (Box 52, Folder 5)
- Partnerships: CEO partnership, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
- Partnerships: Kettering Foundation negotiated investment strategy, Circa 1980 (Box 52, Folder 7)
- Partnerships: dateline, 1983 (Box 52, Folder 8)
- Partnerships: President's Task Force on Private Sector Initiatives, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 9)
- Partnerships: triangular partnerships, Circa 1982 (Box 52, Folder 10)
- Fundraising: fundraising, 1982-1984 (Box 52, Folder 11)
- Cities: Baltimore, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 1)
- Cities: Cincinnati, 1979-1984 (Box 53, Folder 2)
- Cities: Dayton, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Cities: Eugene, Oregon, 1981-1982 (Box 53, Folder 4)
- Cities: McKees Rocks, Penna, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 5)
- Cities: New York, 1981-1982 (Box 53, Folder 6)
- Cities: Pittsburgh, 1980-1984 (Box 53, Folder 7)
- Cities: Portland, Oregon, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 8)
- Cities: Salem, Oregon, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 9)
- Citizen Participation 1960-1975: Planning with the poor, 1964-1966 (Box 54, Folder 1)
- Citizen Participation 1960-1975: Marris, the Strategies of Reform, 1964 December (Box 54, Folder 2)
- Citizen Participation 1960-1975: Adm. Decent. and Citizen Control notes for pamphlets, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 3)
- Citizen Participation 1960-1975: Hallman, Future of Poverty Program "background", 1968 December (Box 54, Folder 4)
- Citizen Participation 1960-1975: Federally finance Citizen Participation, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 5)
- Citizen Participation 1967-69, 1967-1969 (Box 54, Folder 6)
- Citizen Participation 1960-1975: Citizen Participation in urban renewal, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 7)
- Citizen Participation [1/3], 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 8)
- Citizen Participation [2/3], 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 9)
- Citizen Participation [3/3], 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 10)
- Citizen Participation: Decent. papers, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 1)
- Citizen Participation: Articles on neighborhood decentralization, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 2)
- Citizen Participation: OED-funded studies, 1968-1969 (Box 55, Folder 3)
- International: IULA Zagreb Conference, 1971-1972 (Box 55, Folder 4)
- International: Sweden, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
- International: Yugoslavia, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 6)
- International: Netherlands, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 7)
- International: IULA general, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 8)
- International: Canada, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 9)
- International: Finland, 1971 (Box 55, Folder 10)
- International: Great Britain, 1969 (Box 55, Folder 11)
- International: neighborhoods Great Britain, 1975-1981 (Box 55, Folder 12)
- Supplies needed for workshop, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 13)
- Volunteers, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 14)
- Board Training, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 1)
- Negotiated development strategy, 1980-1981 (Box 56, Folder 2)
- Partnerships - coalitions, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 3)
- University consortium for neighborhood research, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 4)
- American Enterprise Institute, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Book on neighborhoods, 1957-1974 (Box 56, Folder 6)
- Reference material for book on neighborhoods, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 7)
- Bibliographies, 1971-1981 (Box 56, Folder 8)
- Neighborhood facilities and municipal decentralization Center for Government Studies, 1971 March (Box 56, Folder 9)
- Politics--Governance: John Mudd's article, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 10)
- Service Delivery, 1981-1982 (Box 56, Folder 11)
- Metropolitan Perspective, 1970-1972 (Box 56, Folder 12)
- Economic Development and Law Center Report, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 1)
- Local Government: Birmington, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 2)
- Local Government: California Muncipal Advisory Councils, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 3)
- Evaluation Techniques: Evaluation of Citizen Participation, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 4)
- Evaluation Techniques: Management planning, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
- Citizen Participation: University of Pennyslvania CDBG study--Citizen Participation report, 1980-1982 (Box 57, Folder 6)
- Citizen Participation: Bibliography, undated (Box 57, Folder 7)
- Citizen Participation: Civic Education, 1981-1983 (Box 57, Folder 8)
- Citizen Participation reports, 1979 May - 1979 June (Box 57, Folder 9)
- Nat'l Conf. on Citizen Participation, 1984 January 26-29 (Box 57, Folder 10)
- National Conference on Citizen Participation, 1978 September 28 - 1978 October 1 (Box 58, Folder 1)
- Citizen Participation misc., undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
- Citizen Participation Handbook, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 3)
- Irvine Community Associations by Michael M. Hertel, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
- Minigovernments a research proposal [1/2], 1974 (Box 58, Folder 5)
- Minigovernments a research proposal [2/2], 1974 (Box 58, Folder 6)
- Citizen Participation Food and Drug Administration, undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
- Federal Citizen Participation, 1971-1984 (Box 58, Folder 8)
- Citizens and Highway Planning, 1972-1976 (Box 59, Folder 1)
- NIMH Research on metropolitan, citizen, work, etc., 1982 (Box 59, Folder 2)
- Federal Budget, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 3)
- Journal of Community Action, 1981-1983 (Box 59, Folder 4)
- Austria, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
- Germany, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
- Misc. Authors: Public Administration theory A-L (authors), circa 1960 - circa 1970 (Box 59, Folder 7)
- Misc. Authors: Public Administration theory M-Z (authors), 1969 - 1970 (Box 60, Folder 1)
- Misc. Authors: Weiler on West Germany, 1971-1975 (Box 60, Folder 2)
- Misc. Authors: Geiger, 1967-1969 (Box 60, Folder 3)
- Misc. Authors: Joseph F. Zimmerman, 1970-1976 (Box 60, Folder 4)
- Articles by Joseph F. Zimmerman, 1974-1980 (Box 61, Folder 1)
- Articles by Joseph F. Zimmerman, 1974-1975 (Box 61, Folder 2)
- Articles by Joseph F. Zimmerman, 1966-1976 (Box 61, Folder 3)
- The Massachusetts Town Meeting a Tenacious Institution by Joseph F. Zimmerman, 1967-1970 (Box 61, Folder 4)
- Center for Government Studies: Minutes of Board Meetings, 1970-1975 (Box 61, Folder 5)
- Center for Government Studies: Four Year Report, 1969-1973 (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Center for Government Studies: Report of Activities, 1969-1974 (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Center for Government Studies: Service Equity, 1972-1981 (Box 61, Folder 8)
- Center for Government Studies: Pamphlets, 1970-1971 (Box 61, Folder 9)
- Center for Government Studies: Neighborhood Decentralization Bulletins, 1973-1975 (Box 62, Folder 1)
- Center for Government Studies: Workshop on Decentralization of Municipal Services, 1970 August 7 (Box 62, Folder 2)
- Center for Government Studies: Public Administration and Neighborhood Control, Boulder Conference, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 3)
- Center for Government Studies: Boulder Conference Material, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Center for Government Studies: New P.A. [public administration], 1970 (Box 62, Folder 5)
- Center for Government Studies: Public Administration Review Curriculum Essays on Citizens, Politics and Administration in Urban Neighborhoods, 1972 October (Box 62, Folder 6)
- Center for Government Studies: Municipal Decentralization Conference, 1970 August 7 (Box 62, Folder 7)
- Center for Government Studies: Community Participation in Public Elementary Schools, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 8)
- Center for Government Studies: State Government a selected bibliography B. Crichton Junes, 1970 February (Box 62, Folder 9)
- Center for Government Studies: Neighborhood facilities and municipal decentralization George Washnis, 1970 February (Box 62, Folder 10)
- Center for Government Studies: Model Cities Impact on Better Communities by George J. Washnis [1/2], undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Center for Government Studies: Model Cities Impact on Better Communities by George J. Washnis [2/2], undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
- Center for Government Studies: Assessment of the Impact of Minneapolis Model City Program, 1974-1975 (Box 63, Folder 3)
- Center for Government Studies: The City Government and Neighborhood Institution, George Washnis, 1970 December 9 (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Center for Government Studies: San Francisco Workshop, 1971 March 11-12 (Box 63, Folder 5)
- Center for Government Studies: Urban Community Development Strategies Conference papers (Columbia, MD), 1971 November 18-19 (Box 63, Folder 6)
- Center for Government Studies: Government by Neighborhoods, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 7)
- Center for Government Studies: Charter Language on Neighborhood Decentralization, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 8)
- Organizational issues of city government Pittsburgh, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 9)
- Pittsburgh Government Study Commission, undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
- Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Charter), undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
- Why Community Involvement? prepared for Dec. 1975 issue of PM (Box 64, Folder 2)
- Management needs of local chief executives, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 3)
- Local chief executives on policy making, 1975 (Box 64, Folder 4)
- Local chief executives perceptions of policy-making and management needs vol. 1, 1975 February (Box 64, Folder 5)
- Center for Governmental Studies Employment and man power training: guaranteed employment, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
- Center for Governmental Studies Employment and man power training: job certificates, undated (Box 64, Folder 7)
- WPA: what is to Learned? by Alden Briscoe, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 8)
- Center for Governmental Studies: State manpower organizations, 1970 July (Box 64, Folder 9)
- Center for Governmental Studies: Metropolitan Manpower Organizations Vol. II, 1970 September (Box 65, Folder 1)
- Center for Governmental Studies: Pamphlets on Manpower programs, 1970-1971 (Box 65, Folder 2)
- Center for Governmental Studies: State organizationa for manpower programs a compilation, undated (Box 65, Folder 3)
- Center for Governmental Studies: metropolitan reports, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
- Center for Governmental Studies: local delivery of manpower services, undated (Box 65, Folder 5)
- Center for Governmental Studies: achieving full employment, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 6)
- The uses of subsidized and transitional employment --ASPA Conferenced in LA, 1973 April 4 (Box 65, Folder 7)
- Analysis of proposed manpower legislation (select subcommittee on Labor), 1972 Feburary 3 (Box 65, Folder 8)
- Congressional testimony, 1973 March 22 (Box 65, Folder 9)
- Implementing public service employment, undated (Box 65, Folder 10)
- Local manpower program areas, undated (Box 65, Folder 11)
- A job for everyone -- conference on national priorities and Federal Economic Program, Washington, 1972 March 10 (Box 65, Folder 12)
- National manpower policies and comprehensive manpower services, undated (Box 65, Folder 13)
- Manpower articles, undated (Box 65, Folder 14)
- Manpower project, undated (Box 65, Folder 15)
- Issues in administering public service employment under The Employment and Manpower Act, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
- Policy issues in Emergency Employment Act of 1971 (S.31) (Box 66, Folder 2)
- A Job for Everyone, 1968 May (Box 66, Folder 3)
- Graduated Family Allowance proposal, undated (Box 66, Folder 4)
- Reducing unemployment and lowering inflation's impact on low income workers, undated (Box 66, Folder 5)
- Sixty Million Jobs by Henry Wallace, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 6)
- Economic security / Anti-poverty, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
- Ideas..., undated (Box 66, Folder 8)
- Development of concepts of community manpower system (Briscoe), undated (Box 66, Folder 9)
- Employment bill, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 10)
- HWH '67 Full Employment Act, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 11)
- Guaranteed jobs, undated (Box 66, Folder 12)
- job certificate program, undated (Box 66, Folder 13)
- Civic Action Institute, 1977 (Box 66, Folder 14)
- Budget process, undated (Box 66, Folder 15)
- Community organizations, undated (Box 66, Folder 16)
- Implementation, undated (Box 66, Folder 17)
- Monitoring and evaluating, undated (Box 66, Folder 18)
- Neighborhood survey, undated (Box 67, Folder 1)
- Assisting citizens to organize, undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
- CP lesson plans, undated (Box 67, Folder 3)
- Introduction to community planning, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
- Maintaining vitality in citizen organization, undated (Box 67, Folder 5)
- Need assessment, undated (Box 67, Folder 6)
- Neighborhood self-help activities, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
- Organizational effectiveness, undated (Box 67, Folder 8)
- Setting goals and objectives, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
- Lesson plans: communications, undated (Box 67, Folder 10)
- Lesson plans: motivation, undated (Box 67, Folder 11)
- Lesson plans: leadership development, undated (Box 67, Folder 12)
- Neighborhood planning a citizen participation guide, 1981 January (Box 67, Folder 13)
- Lesson plans, Undated (Box 67, Folder 14)
- Citizen participation workbook material, Undated (Box 67, Folder 15)
- Community organizing, Undated (Box 67, Folder 16)
- Communications, Undated (Box 67, Folder 17)
- Goal setting process, Undated (Box 67, Folder 18)
- Motivation, Undated (Box 67, Folder 19)
- Research, Undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
- Workshop, conference planning, Undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
- Neighborhood action guides Spanish versions, Undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
- (working papers) Community organizing views of three practitioners, Undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
- (working papers) Community organizing views of three practitioners, undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
- CP in local budget process, undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Civic Action Institute publications, 1980-1981 (Box 68, Folder 7)
- Facing the issues, undated (Box 68, Folder 8)
- Misc. publications, undated (Box 68, Folder 9)
- No Heat No Rent an urban solar and energy conservation manual, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 10)
- NUSA, circa 1990s (Box 68, Folder 11)
- NUSA Conference and tour schedule, circa 1990s (Box 68, Folder 12)
- Speech for NUSA conference, 1995 May 27 (Box 68, Folder 13)
- NUSA [1/3], 1995 (Box 68, Folder 14)
- NUSA [2/3], 1995 (Box 69, Folder 1)
- NUSA [3/3], 1995 (Box 69, Folder 2)
- NUSA Conference, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 3)
- NUSA, 1996-2003 (Box 69, Folder 4)
- Civic Action Institute, undated (Box 69, Folder 5)
- Comprehensive urban program, undated (Box 69, Folder 6)
- How urban coordination came about short story, undated (Box 69, Folder 7)
- urban coordination essay, undated (Box 69, Folder 8)
- Research on CBUS and PSE, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 1)
- Jobs certificates, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 2)
- Citizen participation- cities: citizen participation in the capital budgeting process a study of six cities, 1986 October (Box 70, Folder 3)
- Citizen participation- cities: Albuquerque, N.M., undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
- Citizen participation- cities: Baltimore, MD, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
- Citizen participation- cities: Celeveland, OH, undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
- Citizen participation- cities: Dayton, OH, undated (Box 70, Folder 7)
- Citizen participation- cities: Dayton, OH, undated (Box 70, Folder 8)
- Citizen participation- cities: New York, NY, undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
- Citizen participation- cities: Pasadena, CA, undated (Box 70, Folder 10)
- Citizen participation- cities: Phoenix, AZ, undated (Box 71, Folder 1)
- Citizen participation- cities: Portland, OR, undated (Box 71, Folder 2)
- Citizen participation- cities: St. Paul, MN, undated (Box 71, Folder 3)
- Citizen participation- cities: Seattle, WA, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
- Citizen participation- cities: South Florida, undated (Box 71, Folder 5)
- Citizen participation- cities: Tacoma, WA, undated (Box 71, Folder 6)
- Citizen participation- cities: Citizen participation Federal contacts, undated (Box 71, Folder 7)
- Issues: Federal citizen participation, undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
- Issues: Federal emergency management agency, undated (Box 71, Folder 9)
- Issues: U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
- Issues: U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, undated (Box 71, Folder 11)
- Issues: U.S. Department of Transportation, undated (Box 71, Folder 12)
- Citizen Participation topics: Guides for grassroots action, undated (Box 71, Folder 13)
- Citizen Participation topics: Citizen participation bibliography, undated (Box 71, Folder 14)
- Citizen Participation topics: Citizen roles on city budget making, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 1)
- Citizen Participation topics: Citizenship and public administration, undated (Box 72, Folder 2)
- Citizen Participation topics: CP training materials, undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
- Citizen Participation topics: Civic Action Institute material, undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
- Citizen Participation topics: Environmental and urban issues, undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
- Citizen Participation topics: Planning with neighborhoods, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
- Citizen Participation topics: Volunteers, undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
- Poverty program 1964-1966: History [1/2] (Box 72, Folder 8)
- Poverty program 1964-1966: History [2/2] (Box 72, Folder 9)
- Poverty program 1964-1966: Federal Task Force on Poverty (Box 72, Folder 10)
- Poverty Program 1964-1966: Federal Task Force on Poverty memos by Hallman (Box 72, Folder 11)
- Poverty Program 1964-1966: Planning paper (Box 73, Folder 1)
- Poverty Program 1964-1967 Rural North Caroline: North Carolina (Box 73, Folder 2)
- Poverty Program 1964-1967 Rural North Caroline: Rural poverty (Box 73, Folder 3)
- Poverty Program 1966-1968 (Box 73, Folder 4)
- Poverty Program 1966-1968: Berkeley Conference (Box 73, Folder 5)
- Poverty Program 1966-1968: Papers on NAPA conference, 1970 April (Box 73, Folder 6)
- Future of Poverty program, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 1)
- U.S. Senate Poverty Program Study, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 2)
- U.S. Senate Poverty Program Study: Budget, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 3)
- U.S. Senate Poverty Program Study: Issues, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 4)
- U.S. Senate Poverty Program Study: Reflections, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 5)
- U.S. Senate Poverty Program Study: House Hearings, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 6)
- U.S. Senate Poverty Program Study, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 7)
- Community Action Program workbook, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 8)
- Community Action Program Guide Vol 1, 1965 February (Box 75, Folder 1)
  note on post-it attached to the book "marginal notes by Howard Hallman"
- Detailed finding study to determine effects of cap programs on selected communities and their low-income residents prepared for Office of Economic Opportunity, 1967 March (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Brandeis Cap Study [1/2], 1969 (Box 75, Folder 3)
- Brandeis Cap Study [2/2], 1969 (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Mac Legerton on organizing, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
- National Anti-Poverty Strategy, undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
- Needs Assessment (loose papers), 1984 (Box 75, Folder 7)
- Community Corporations, undated (Box 76, Folder 1)
- Community Corporations: Neighborhood Corporation draft manual, 1969 April (Box 76, Folder 2)
- Neighborhood Centers; OSTI, undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
- Neighborhood Centers, undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
- Neighborhood Center Pilot Program ABT study, undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
- C.D.B.G. Citizen Participation [1/3], undated (Box 76, Folder 6)
- C.D.B.G. Citizen Participation [2/3], undated (Box 77, Folder 1)
- C.D.B.G. Citizen Participation [3/3], undated (Box 77, Folder 2)
- RERC on Housing, undated (Box 77, Folder 3)
- H.U.D. Neighborhoods [1/2], circa 1970s (Box 77, Folder 4)
- H.U.D. Neighborhoods [2/2], circa 1970s (Box 77, Folder 5)
- H.U.D. Neighborhood Decentralization, 1984-1985 (Box 77, Folder 6)